tilt.com 2017-05-31

# Tilt Privacy Policy

**Updated: August 5, 2016**

## Introduction

This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, store, use, share, and protect your personal information. It also lays out the choices and rights you have with respect to this information. This Privacy Policy applies to the Site, Applications and Services. All capitalized terms shall have the meaning set forth in the [Tilt Terms](http://policies.tilt.com/global/terms.html) unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy. 

## Information We Collect

### _Information You Give Us_

We collect, store, and use information you give us when you create an account and use the Tilt Services. This includes:

  * Contact information, like your name, email address, phone number, mailing address, and your city, state, and country of residence.
  * Financial information, like your bank account information or payment card information and home and billing address.
  * Additional personal information, like your date of birth or Social Security number. 
  * Your username and password. Please choose a strong password that you don’t use anywhere else.
  * Information sent to us by the device(s) you use to access our Services, including data on the pages you access, your location, mobile network information, device type, device ID, standard web log data, and your Internet protocol (IP) address. Although this information is generally non-identifying, where it can be used to identify you we treat it subject to the same safeguards that we apply to personal information.
  * Your Facebook connect credentials (and information that you authorize Facebook share with us though permissions).
  * Cell phone contacts information when you grant us access to store and use your information. We specifically will access the names, phone numbers and email addresses in your phonebook.
  * Your email address book when you invite your email contacts to try Tilt.
  * Other information that you provide to us, like email messages, User Content and customer support requests. 

Where you provide information to us about a third party, such as your friends, you must obtain the consent of that person to the use of their information in accordance with this Privacy Policy before you provide it to us. 

### _Information Sent to Us by Third Parties_

You may log into our Services using Facebook Connect or other similar third-party applications. These applications authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us, which varies from service to service. We collect, store, and use this information as described in this Privacy Policy.

We may also collect information about you from other sources as permitted by law, including credit bureaus, identity verification services, or our payment processors, and combine that data with information we collect on our Services. 

## Why We Collect This Information

We collect personal information about you so that we can provide secure, smooth, efficient, and customized Services. We may use your personal information to:

  * Provide you with access to and use of our Services.
  * Enable Payees to promote campaigns both on and off the Tilt Services.
  * Ensure our records are accurate, complete, and verified by third parties, when necessary.
  * We use Facebook Content, cell phone contacts and your personal information to connect you with friends and contacts on the Tilt Services by making it easier to invite others to and make Transactions (as well as helping us improve our services and fight fraud). For example, one form of an invitation is Tagging. Another Tilt User may invite you to a transaction you are not otherwise a part of by Tagging you. When you are tagged on the Tilt Services, a link to your Tilt profile will appear in where you are tagged and you will receive a notification about the tag. You may manage certain contact preferences and notifications in your account settings.
  * This information will be used to customize the services for you, other Tilt Users and non-Tilt Users invited to the Tilt Services by existing Tilt users.
  * We may later tailor Content, such as by highlighting Transactions or other Tilt Users to you.
  * Give you awesome customer support.
  * Process transactions and send you notices about them.
  * Customize, measure, and improve our Services.
  * Resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, and collect fees.
  * Prevent, detect, and investigate potentially prohibited or illegal activities.
  * Enforce the [Tilt Terms](http://policies.tilt.com/global/terms-of-use.html), Processor Terms, [Community Guidelines](http://policies.tilt.com/community-guidelines.html), [Organizer Guidelines](http://policies.tilt.com/organizer-guidelines.html), [Contributor Guidelines](http://policies.tilt.com/contributor-guidelines.html), [Acceptable Use Policy](http://policies.tilt.com/us/acceptable-use-policy), and our other policies.
  * Deliver targeted marketing, service update notices, promotional offers, marketing and Transaction updates, based on your communication preferences (email, phone, text, etc.).
  * Enable you to invite your friends to try the Services via various means (such as text message, email and otherwise), if you’d like. 
  * So Tilt and Payees can send you things in the mail like promotional materials, rewards, or purchases.

## How We Share This Information

### _Information Shared on the Services Generally_

The Tilt Services are social and community focused and are designed to enable you to do things with others and to share Transactions with others. To that end, the default sharing level setting is public, unless you are contributing to a private campaign. You can change the privacy setting for an individual Transaction when paying or for a campaign during the campaign creating process. You can also change the privacy setting for a campaign after it is created.

Tilt offers three different sharing levels on the Tilt Services: 

  * Public. When you publically transact using Pay or Request Money, your transactions are viewable by all Tilt Users and more broadly on the Internet, such as on search engines. When you contribute to a public Organize/Collect campaign, all transactions are public. You cannot privately contribute to a public Organize/Collect campaign.
  * Friends Only. When you select this setting, your transactions will only be viewable on the Tilt Services to those Tilt Users that you are also Facebook Friends with. This is the case, even if those Tilt Users do not follow you on the Tilt Services.
  * Participants Only / Private: When you pay a Tilt User or contribute to a Request Money transaction, you may select that the transaction stays private to only those parties that were a part of that collective transaction. If you are contributing to a private Organize / Collect campaign, your transaction will be viewable to those that also contributed to it and those that have the link to the campaign.

See our Sharing Levels FAQ to [learn more](https://support.tilt.com/hc/en-us/articles/206194598-What-s-the-difference-between-public-and-private-tilt-pages-).

### _Information Shared with Payees_

When you transact on the Tilt Services, your name, the amount of your Transaction, email address and date of the Transaction are shared with the Payee. Your Transactions will be visible to others on the Tilt Services, according to the sharing level, but will only provide your name and show you joined the campaign (amounts are aggregated into groups of people, but may sometimes be determined).

We sometimes share partial payment information with Tilt Pro Payees, including the last four digits of your payment card number, so that they can do things like fulfill your order, process refunds, and dispute chargebacks.

### _Information Shared with Third Parties_

We may share your personal information and financial information with:

  * Payment processors or banking partners in order to facilitate your financial transactions or as required by credit card association rules. 
  * Credit bureaus and collection agencies to report account information, as permitted by law.
  * Verified nonprofit organizations so that they can send you a receipt for your tax-deductible contribution.
  * Affiliates or other trusted third parties that process personal information for us or help with our business operations, such as marketing, fraud prevention, compliance, and technology services. 
  * Other third parties when we believe it is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with the law; (b) protect any person from death or serious bodily injury; (c) prevent fraud or abuse of Tilt or our users; or (d) protect Tilt's property rights. If we’re going to release your information in response to legal process, our policy is to provide reasonable advance notice, along with a copy of the request, unless prohibited from doing so by law or court order (e.g., an order under 18 U.S.C. § 2705(b)). Where prior notice is prohibited, our intent is to notify affected users after the non-disclosure period has lapsed. We may disclose information without prior notice if we believe it’s necessary to prevent imminent and serious bodily harm to a person. Nothing in this Privacy Policy is intended to limit any legal objections or defenses our users may have to efforts by third parties to compel disclosure of information, including legal orders from the government.
  * Companies we plan to merge with or to be acquired by. Should such an event occur, the new entity will step into our shoes for purposes of this Privacy Policy.
  * Other third parties with your consent.

As noted above, Tilt shares information with Payees. Otherwise, Tilt will not provide any of your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes except with your prior consent. For example, we may from time to time offer co-branded experiences with other companies on the Services, and if we obtain your consent to provide your information to those companies for the identified uses in the consent, then we may share your information with them to be used according to the consents.

We reserve the right to anonymize your personal data and may share aggregated, non-personally identifiable information publicly and with our partners, including publishers, advertisers, or affiliated sites. For example, we may share information with others to show trends about the general use of the Services.

### _Promotional Uses_

We may publically feature your campaign if it is public (but not if its private) and contributions to that campaign on an [examples](https://www.tilt.com/examples) like campaign on the Services. For TiltPro Organizers, we may publically feature your campaign or you as a user on educational and client list pages and in marketing and promotional materials, including the trademarks you use on our Services.

## Your Privacy Preferences

Tilt lets you set your preferences for the use and sharing of your information, including how or when we and Payees contact you. If you don’t want to have personal information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). You may still see generic, non-targeted ads after opting out. If you don’t want to receive newsletters, campaign updates, or marketing communications from us, simply indicate so in your notifications panel. We may call you if you give us your phone number, such as for customer support purposes.

Please contact us at privacy@tilt.com if you would like us to (i) contact you by phone or to (ii) delete your imported phonebook contact (its an all or nothing thing). You can also reach out to us for other privacy related support at this email address.

You can review and edit your Personal Information on our Services by adjusting your profile information on Tilt by adjusting your profile information here and on TiltPro by visiting the Settings section of the Admin tab when you’re logged in to your account.

## Facebook Friend Notifications

If you grant Tilt permission to access your friend information from Facebook, we may use that information to (i) notify on the Tilt Service those people that are your Facebook friends that are on Tilt and (ii) to show your transactions on Tilt to your Facebook friends on Tilt when you select the Friends privacy setting.

## Cookie Policy

Like many other websites, we may place small data files on your computer or other device. These data files may be cookies, pixel tags, or other local storage provided by your browser or associated applications. We use these technologies to:

  * Recognize you as a customer.
  * Customize our Services, content, advertising, marketing, and targeting, and measure their effectiveness.
  * Help ensure that your account security is not compromised, mitigate risk and prevent fraud, and promote trust and safety across our Website and the Services. 

We may use both session and persistent cookies. Session cookies expire and no longer have any effect when you log out of your account or close your browser. Persistent cookies remain on your device until you erase them or they expire. We may tie the information gathered to our users' personally identifiable information.

Some browsers make it possible for you to signal that you don’t want your internet browsing activity to be tracked. There is currently no consensus on how to best honor these signals, so we don’t respond to “do not track” requests at this time. Declining our cookies may interfere with your use of our Services.

Our third-party partners also may employ cookies. The use of cookies by others is not covered by this Privacy Policy. 

## How We Protect Your Information

We and our [cloud provider](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/) protect your information using physical, technical, and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, and alteration. Safeguards include firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to the data centers, and information access authorization controls.

When you enter financial information (such as a payment card number or your bank account information) on our Services, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

To the extent we transmit and store your cardholder data, we do so under the most stringent credit card security standard: PCI Compliance Level 1. A PCI-certified auditor verified and awarded us this level of security and compliance. 

We work hard to secure your data, but nobody is perfect. If you discover a vulnerability in our Services, we would be grateful for your report and encourage you to let us know immediately. To report a bug, please email security@tilt.com. 

Learn more about our [security practices](http://policies.tilt.com/security).

## Retention of Your Information

We retain information for accounts as long as it’s important to our operations. We may retain information from disabled accounts to improve our services, comply with the law, prevent fraud, collect fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with investigations, enforce the Tilt Terms, and take other actions permitted by law. If we anonymize your information, we may retain that anonymized information indefinitely. The information we retain about you will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the [Tilt Terms](http://policies.tilt.com/global/terms-of-use.html).

## Social Sharing

You can share things on the Services through other services you use like Facebook, Twitter, and WhatsApp. Please be aware of your settings on those other services. They may collect your IP address, track pages you visit on our site, and set cookies, among other things. 

Our Services include social features and widgets that are provided either by Tilt or a third party. Your use of these features is governed by the privacy policy of the service providing them and we are not responsible for their privacy practices. You are responsible for sharing your and other people’s personal information on these sites.

## Rights of California Residents

California residents can request a list of what personal information (if any) we’ve disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year, and the names and addresses of those third parties. You can make a request only once a year, and you don't have to pay for it. To make your request, send an email to privacy@tilt.com or send a written request to Legal Department, Tilt.com, Inc., 370 Townsend Street, San Francisco, CA 94107.

## Our Services are Global

Any and all information on the Services may be transmitted, processed, and stored in the United States or in other parts of the world by Tilt or Tilt subsidiaries according to this Privacy Policy.

## Updating This Privacy Policy

We periodically review this Privacy Policy and may change it from time to time. If we make material changes, we’ll notify you by posting a notice on our website and Services. If you continue using our Services after the notice is posted, you’re accepting the new Privacy Policy. You may request past versions of this privacy policy by emailing us at happiness@tilt.com

## Reach Out To Us

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or any feedback for us, email us at privacy@tilt.com. We’d love to hear from you. This is the Privacy Policy of Tilt.com, Inc. We are located at 370 Townsend Street, San Francisco, CA 94107.
